Finding Aid for R. W. Fleming papers, 1920-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- University of Michigan President 1967-1978
  - Personal Papers from president's office
    - Correspondence
      - 1978-1979
        - Accolades/appreciations/criticism (Box 15)
        - Book materials: humor (Box 15)
        - Condolence letters (Box 15)
        - Friends (Box 15)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
        - Professional: general (Box 15)
        - Recommendations (Box 15)
        - Retirement plans (Box 15)
        - Speeches and statements (Box 15)
        - Travel: leaves of absence (Box 15)
    - Essays never completed (Box 15)
    - Family
      - General (Box 15)
      - Mrs. Jeannette Boutwell (Box 15)
      - Sally Fleming (Box 15)
    - Sesquicentennial film (regarding) June 5, 1967 (Box 15)
      (film featured Robben Fleming and Tom Harmon)
    - Inauguration 1967-1968
      - General (Box 15)
      - Congratulatory letters (Box 15)
    - Inquiries (miscellaneous) (Box 15)
    - Interviews, 3 folders (Box 15)
    - Invitations accepted
      - 1967-1968
        - Alumni (Box 15)
        - Commencement (Box 15)
        - General (Box 16)
        - University/student (Box 16)
      - 1968-1969
        - Alumni (Box 16)
        - Commencement (Box 16)
        - General (Box 16)
        - University/student (Box 16)
      - 1969-1970
        - Alumni (Box 16)
        - Commencement (Box 16)
        - General (Box 16)
        - University/student (Box 16)
      - 1970-1971
        - Alumni (Box 16)
        - Commencement (Box 16)
        - General (Box 16)
        - University/student groups (Box 16)
      - 1971-1972
        - Alumni (Box 16)
        - Commencement (Box 16)
        - University/Student groups (Box 16)
      - 1972-1973
        - Alumni (Box 16)
        - Commencement (Box 16)
        - General (Box 16)
        - University/student groups (Box 16)
      - 1973-1974
        - Alumni (Box 16)
        - General (Box 16)
        - University/student groups (Box 16)
      - 1974-1975
        - Alumni (Box 16)
        - Commencement (Box 16)
        - General (Box 16)
        - University/student groups (Box 16)
      - 1975-1976
        - Alumni (Box 16)
        - Commencement (Box 16)
        - General (Box 16)
        - University/student groups (Box 16)
      - 1976-1977
        - Alumni (Box 16)
        - Commencement (Box 16)
        - General (Box 17)
        - University/student groups (Box 17)
      - 1977-1978
        - Alumni (Box 17)
        - General (Box 17)
        - University/student groups (Box 17)
      - 1978-1979
        - Alumni (Box 17)
        - Commencement (Box 17)
        - General (Box 17)
        - University/student groups (Box 17)
    - Letters to: deans and students (Box 17)
    - Lists (Box 17)
    - Memberships: civic and social (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
    - Newell, Barbara (Box 17)
    - Positions (job offer received and considered)
      - General (Box 17)
      - University of California (Box 17)
    - President's Pay Advisory Committee, 3 folders; 1 volumes (Box 17)
    - Publications: miscellaneous correspondence (Box 17)
    - R.W.F. Fund Account no. 32301 (Box 17)
    - Resignations
      - University of Michigan (includes material on CBP appointment and Chrysler Corporation tribute), 3 folders (Box 17)
      - Corporation on Public Broadcasting (CPB) (Box 18)
    - Retirement plans (Box 18)
    - Speeches (chronological order)
      - Lists (Box 18)
      - 1967 (Box 18)
      - 1968, 4 folders (Box 18)
      - 1969 (Box 18)
      - 1970 (Box 18)
      - 1971, 2 folders (Box 18)
      - 1972, 2 folders (Box 18)
      - 1973 (Box 18)
      - 1974 (Box 19)
      - 1975, 2 folders (Box 19)
      - 1976 (Box 19)
      - 1977 (Box 19)
      - 1978 (Box 19)
      - 1979 (Box 19)
    - Speeches (topical order)
      - Alumni and contributors (Box 19)
      - Branch campuses (Dearborn and Flint) (Box 19)
      - Campus (Ann Arbor) (Box 19)
      - Campus (Conferences held on campus or in Ann Arbor) (Box 19)
      - Campus (students and staff) (Box 19)
      - Churches and religious groups (Box 19)
      - Service clubs (Box 19)
    - Speeches: reactions to (Box 19)
    - Testimonies
      - May 8, 1969 ("Statement on Student Unrest," U.S. House of Representatives, Special Subcommittee on Education) (Box 19)
      - July 15, 1970 ("Remarks Before Presidential Committee on Campus Tensions") (Box 19)
      - August 12, 1974 (J. O'Hara's Special Subcommittee on Education--House Committee on Education and Labor) (Box 19)
    - Travel records
      - 1970 Australia and Hawaii (Box 19)
      - 1971 Korea (Box 19)
      - 1973 Scotland (Box 19)
      - 1974
        - China and Japan, 4 folders (Box 20)
        - Germany (Box 20)
        - Venezuela (Box 20)
      - 1975 Russia (Box 20)
      - 1976
        - China (Regents and Mrs. Fleming) (Box 20)
        - Taiwan (Box 20)
      - 1977
        - Germany (Box 20)
        - Israel (Box 20)
        - Yugoslavia, 3 folders (Box 20)
      - 1978
        - Saudi Arabia (Box 20)
        - South Africa (Box 20)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 20)
    - University of Michigan miscellanea (Box 20)
    - University of Wisconsin (includes bail money material) (Box 20)
- Corporation for Public Broadcasting
  The Corporation for Public Broadcasting series are files from his years as President of the organization and pertaining to the funding received from the Annenberg Foundation.
  - Miscellaneous
    - Board of Directors 1981 (Box 21)
    - Correspondence
      - May 1982 (Box 21)
      - February 1982 (Box 21)
      - January 1982 (Box 21)
      - August-December 1981 (Box 21)
    - General correspondence 1981-1982, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - American Council on Education (Box 21)
    - Annenberg Project 1988 (Box 21)
    - Financial aid for higher education film project 1979 (Box 21)
    - McGraw-Hill 1981 (Box 21)
    - Statements
      - On implementation of 1978 Telecommunications Act, March 25, 1981 (Box 21)
      - Before House and Senate appropriations committees (Box 21)
      - Concerning H.R. 3238 and H.R. 2774 April 1981 (Box 21)
      - Concerning Senate Bill 720 April 6, 1981 (Box 21)
    - Universidade de Brasilia 1981-1982 (Box 21)
    - Universities 1981 (Box 21)
  - Annenberg Project
    - Background Materials
      - General, 2 folders (Box 21)
      - John Witherspoon history 1981, 1984, 1987, 3 folders (Box 21)
    - Correspondence
      - Agreement Extension Settlement 1991 (Box 21)
      - American Political Science Assoc. 1983 (Box 21)
      - British Open University 1980-1987 (Box 21)
      - Budget and Funding 1981 (Box 21)
      - CPB/ASC Council 1981-1982 (Box 21)
      - CPB/ASC Program 1983 (Box 21)
      - CPB/ASC Project Task Force 1980-1981, 5 folders (Box 21)
      - Council on Library Resources 1983 (Box 21)
      - David Saxon Talks 1982 (Box 21)
      - Director's Discretionary Grants 1982 (Box 21)
      - Evaluation of Project 1985 (Box 21)
      - Fellowships and Awards 1984 (Box 21)
      - Five Colleges 1985 (Box 21)
      - Don Foresta 1982 (Box 21)
      - Lewis Freedman 1985 (Box 21)
      - Fred Friendly 1982-1983, 1984-1987, 3 folders (Box 21)
      - Funding Announcement 1981 (Box 21)
      - General 1979-1987, 1991, 11 folders (Box 21)
      - Grants 1981-1982, 3 folders (Box 21)
      - Guidelines 1984 (Box 21)
      - Harvard University 1982 (Box 21)
      - Internal Organization 1980-1981 (Box 22)
      - Johns Hopkins University 1982 (Box 22)
      - Kalba Bowen Associates, Inc. 1980 (Box 22)
      - Mara Mayor
        - General 1983-1987, 1989, 6 folders (Box 22)
        - Distribution 1984-1986 (Box 22)
      - Martin Meyerson 1982 (Box 22)
      - National Archives 1985 (Box 22)
      - Outside Correspondence 1979-1981, 2 folders (Box 22)
      - PBS (Public Broadcasting Service) / FI (Films Incorporated) Contract 1986 (Box 22)
      - PBS Problems 1987 (Box 22)
      - Planning 1984, 1986 (Box 22)
      - Program Rights 1981-1982 (Box 22)
      - Project '87 1987 (Box 22)
      - Project Proposals 1981 (Box 22)
      - Research and Evaluation 1981-1983 (Box 22)
      - Rockefeller Foundation 1983 (Box 22)
      - Staff Retreat 1985-1986 (Box 22)
      - Elizabeth W. Stone 1982 (Box 22)
      - University of Michigan 1992 (Box 22)
      - University of Mid America 1979-1981 (Box 22)
    - Interviews with Robben Fleming 1985, 1986 (Box 22)
    - Notes on Project Proposals 1982 (Box 22)
    - Reports
      - 1983 and Beyond (Box 22)
      - Director's Report 1981-1983, 2 folders (Box 22)
      - The Future of the Annenberg/CPB Project 1988 (Box 22)
      - MIT (Box 22)
      - Project Highlights 1982 (Box 22)
      - Project Proposals 1984 (Box 22)
      - Television Education in Perspective, by R.W. Fleming 1981 (Box 22)
  - Consultant Agreements (CPB) 1989-1991 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence
    - CPB Organization (Box 22)
    - Senate Amendments 1988 (Box 22)
    - David A. Stewart 1982, 1985, 1987 (Box 22)
  - Additional CPB / Annenberg Project files (Box 23)
    (unprocessed)
    (continued)
  - Additional CPB / Annenberg Project files (Box 24)
  - Additional CPB / Annenberg Project files (Box 25)
  - Additional CPB / Annenberg Project files (Box 26)
  - Additional CPB / Annenberg Project files (Box 27)
  - Additional CPB / Annenberg Project files (Box 28)
- Other Organizational Activities
  The Other Organizational Activities series documents Fleming's involvement after leaving the University with such organizations as the Kellogg Foundation, the Michigan Commission on Health Care Provider Malpractice and Malpractice Insurance, National Institute for Dispute Resolution, and the S.C. Johnson Foundation. In this series, as well, there are files relating to Fleming's continuing interest and involvement in University of Michigan issues and projects.
  - Kellogg Foundation
    - Correspondence 1982-1986, 5 folders (Box 29)
    - Correspondence with Fellows
      - General correspondence 1983-1986, 3 folders (Box 29)
      - Baber, Willie (Box 29)
      - Calabrese, Diane (Box 29)
      - Clohesy, Stephanie (Box 29)
      - Hyde, Michael (Box 29)
      - Kivnick, Helen, 3 folders (Box 29)
      - Linkow, Peter (Box 29)
      - Nash, Ken (Box 29)
      - Nelson, Dan (Box 29)
      - Reed, Ingrid (Box 29)
      - Rogoff, Barbara (Box 29)
    - Advisory Committee 1986 (Box 29)
    - Forum II 1986-1987 (Box 29)
    - Group IV Advisory Committee, final reports 1987 (Box 29)
    - Groups V, VI, and VII fellows (Box 29)
    - Interview materials (Box 29)
    - Program on Corporate Responsibility 1984 (Box 29)
    - Seminars I-VII 1984-1986, 7 folders (Box 29)
  - Labor Institute of Public Affairs
    - AFL-CIO, 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Reports 1982, 1983, 2 folders (Box 29)
  - Michigan State Employees Association
    - Correspondence 1983-1984 (Box 30)
    - Court reports, 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Representation service fees 1984 (Box 30)
    - Representation objector procedure (Box 30)
  - National Commission for Higher Education Correspondence 1981-1982, 3 folders (Box 30)
  - National Institute for Dispute Resolution 1985 (Box 30)
  - UAW-Legal Services Plan
    - Correspondence and reports 1984-1987 (Box 30)
    - Administrative Committee meeting reports 1983-1984 (Box 30)
  - Commission on Health Care Provider Malpractice and Malpractice Insurance
    - Correspondence 1985, 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Reports 1985, 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Final Report 1985 (Box 30)
    - Reactions 1986 (Box 30)
    - Notes and memos 1986 (Box 30)
    - Tort reform and preparation of bills 1986 (Box 30)
    - Malpractice bills passed (Box 30)
    - Concluding report 1986 (Box 30)
    - Reports, correspondence and speeches 1986, 3 folders (Box 30)
    - Malpractice study--correspondence 1987 (Box 30)
    - Clippings (Box 30)
    - Medical Liability Trust 1988 (Box 30)
    - Memos 1989-1990 (Box 30)
    - Final Report 1990 (draft) (Box 30)
  - National Institute for Dispute Resolution (NIDR)
    - Legal Education (Box 31)
    - MacArthur Foundation (Box 31)
    - School of Natural Resources (UM) Conflict Resolution (Box 31)
    - Science Court 1981-1983 (Box 31)
    - Stoner Foundation (Box 31)
    - University of Wisconsin (Box 31)
    - Background (Box 31)
    - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes 1981-1982, 2 folders (Box 31)
    - Correspondence
      - Administrative Conference of the U.S. 1987 (Box 31)
      - American Arbitration Association 1981-1987 (Box 31)
      - American Bar Association 1982-1984 (Box 31)
      - Board of Directors 1987-1988 (Box 31)
      - Center for Public Resources 1981-1984 (Box 31)
      - Chairperson Search 1986 (Box 31)
      - Council on the Role of Courts Conference 1982 (Box 31)
      - Madeline Crohn 1982-1987, 6 folders (Box 31)
      - Endispute 1984 (Box 31)
      - Evaluation of the President 1987 (Box 31)
      - R.W. Fleming 1981-1982 (Box 31)
      - Fleming Speech at Administrative Conference of the U.S. 1987 (Box 31)
      - Funding 1985-1986 (Box 31)
      - General 1982-1987, 1990, 8 folders (Box 31)
      - Institute for Civil Justice-RAND 1987 (Box 31)
      - Bob Jones 1982 (Box 31)
      - NIDR Program 1981-1982, 1985, 1987 (Box 31)
      - William C. Pendleton 1982 (Box 31)
      - Retainers and Fees 1981-1982 (Box 31)
      - Rockefeller Foundation 1980-1981, 1984 (Box 31)
    - Dispute Resolution in Public Policy Administration, Policy and Planning Education Meeting 1984 (Box 31)
    - Family Mediation 1984 (Box 31)
    - Filer Committee 1985 (Box 31)
    - Ford Foundation Proposal 1982 (Box 31)
    - Foundation Meeting February 6, 1985 (Box 31)
    - Funders Meeting, Minutes June 15, 1984 (Box 31)
    - Harvard-American Bar Assoc. Conference on Dispute Settlement 1982 (Box 31)
    - Hewlett Foundation 1982-1987 (Box 31)
    - Higher Education Conference 1984 (Box 31)
    - NIDR's Activities Report 1981 (Box 31)
    - Nursing Home Proposal 1986 (Box 31)
    - Public Interest Mediation Fund 1986 (Box 31)
    - Panel on Dispute Resolution and Public Policy 1983, 3 folders (Box 31)
    - Presidential Candidate (Box 31)
    - Program Planning 1983-1984 (Box 31)
    - Reflections on the ADR Movement, by R.W. Fleming, Lecture 1986 (Box 31)
    - Reflections on NIDR, by R.W. Fleming 1984 (Box 31)
    - Reports
      - Report to Governor Blanchard on the Subject of Health Care Provider Malpractice and Malpractice Insurance 1986 (Box 31)
      - Association of Governing Boards of Universities and Colleges Higher Education Conciliation Project 1986 (Box 31)
  - MacArthur Foundation
    - Background (Box 32)
    - Correspondence 1988-1993, 5 folders (Box 32)
  - Cornell Cooperative Extension
    - Correspondence July 1986-1987, 4 folders (Box 32)
    - Reports 1986-1987, 4 folders (Box 32)
  - Educational Testing Service
    - Correspondence 1983-1986, 5 folders (Box 32)
    - Visiting Committee Reports 1984-1986, 3 folders (Box 32)
  - Harvard Graduate School of Education--Visiting Committee
    - Correspondence 1980-1987, 3 folders (Box 32)
    - Reports 1981, 1987 (Box 32)
  - Kellogg National Fellowship Program, 3 folders (Box 32)
  - S.C. Johnson Foundation
    - Background (Box 33)
    - Correspondence 1983-1989, 7 folders (Box 33)
    - Higher Education Project, Correspondence 1992-1993, 4 folders (Box 33)
    - Miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 33)
  - National Academy of Arbitrators (Box 33)
  - National Association of State Universities Emeriti Project (Box 33)
  - Retired College and University Presidents (Box 33)
  - Society of Professionals in Dispute Resolution (SPIDR) (Box 33)
  - University of Michigan Law School 1980s
    - Correspondence September 1982-June 1987 (Box 33)
    - Boylan, Paul September-October 1984 (Box 33)
    - Burnstein disputes seminar 1983-1984 (Box 33)
    - Cohen, Carl 1984-1987 (Box 33)
    - Douvan, Elizabeth 1985 (Box 33)
    - Fusfield-Roach controversy 1987 (Box 33)
    - Hornback, Bert 1983-1987 (Box 33)
    - Institute for Continuing Legal Education 1983 (Box 33)
    - Kirschner, Curt June 1984-June 1986 (Box 33)
    - Labor Law--teaching materials December 1985 (Box 33)
    - Program on conflict management alternatives 1987 (Box 33)
  - University of Michigan Miscellaneous (largely post-retirement)
    - Communications related to Alumnus Place Project 1985 (Box 33)
    - Institute for Social Research 1983-1986 (Box 33)
    - Journalists in residence (Box 33)
    - Mann, Richard 1984-1985 (Box 33)
    - Medical School-ISR (Threatt) Dispute (Box 33)
    - Miscellaneous 1976-1996 (Box 33)
    - Pena vs. University of Michigan (affirmative action suit) 1984 (Box 33)
    - Rosenthal, Marilyn--malpractice 1987 (Box 33)
    - School of Library and Information Science 1986-1987 (Box 33)
    - Senior Housing 1983-1987 (Box 33)
    - Student code 1988-1990 (Box 33)
    - Sussman-Porter Group for Communications (Box 33)
    - Research 1982-1983 (Box 33)
- Topical Files 1978-2000
  The Topical files is a miscellanea of correspondence and other materials relating both to the University of Michigan, to his work on various committees, and to his consulting on matters of higher education.
  - Academy of Senior Professionals, Ekerd College 1982-1983 (Box 34)
  - American Arbitration Association, Board of Directors 1982 (Box 34)
  - American Association of Community and Junior Colleges 1979 (Box 34)
  - ACLU Lawsuit 1989 (Box 34)
  - American Council on Education 1981-1984, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Association for Study of Higher Education 1982-1983 (Box 34)
  - Atlantic Foundation 2000 (Box 34)
  - Beloit College (earlier materials) (Box 34)
    (include photographs)
  - Beloit College 1982-1986 (Box 34)
  - Beloit College 50th Reunion 1998 (Box 34)
  - Brazil, Percy, MD 1986-1987 (Box 34)
  - Bush Foundation April 1984 (Box 34)
  - Business Higher Education Forum 1981-1982 (Box 34)
  - Carnegie Corporation: US-South African Leader Exchange Program 1978 (Box 34)
  - Cleveland State University 1984-1986 (Box 34)
  - Cohen (Wilbur Cohen) Symposium 1988 (Box 34)
  - Concordia College, Montreal November 1982 (Box 34)
  - Conferences and invitations. 1981 (Box 34)
  - Council for Graduate Schools in the US (Box 34)
  - Council on Michigan Foundations 1987 (Box 34)
  - Doan, Junia 1982-1987 (Box 34)
  - East-West Center 1984-1985 (Box 34)
  - First Presbyterian Church of Ann Arbor--Washtenaw County Black Economic Development League (Box 34)
  - Fleming (State Police file) (Box 34)
  - Ford, Gerald, R., miscellaneous (Box 34)
  - Ford Library (Box 34)
  - Foundation for Teaching Economics, Board of Trustees 1981-1985 (Box 34)
  - Freedman, Lewis (correspondence) 1990-1991 (Box 34)
  - Fund Raising (University of Michigan)
    - Campaign for Michigan 1990-1992 (Box 34)
    - Friends of Radiation Oncology 1991-1992 (Box 34)
    - Friends of the University of Michigan Library 1988-1996, 4 folders (Box 34)
    - University of Michigan Theatre Associates 1992-1993 (Box 34)
  - Historica Critica 1986-1987 (Box 34)
  - Hornback, Bert (correspondence) 1989-1992 (Box 34)
  - Hospital Community Benefit Standards Advisory Committee 1989-1992 (Box 34)
  - Illinois Bar Association November 21, 1986 (Box 34)
  - The Information Society (Jerry L. Salvaggio, ed.), January 1982 (Box 34)
  - Information Symposium, School of Information and Library Studies, University of Michigan 1991-1992 (Box 34)
  - Irvine Group 1987-1992, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Kochen, Thomas A. (MIT) November 1982 (Box 34)
  - Medical Malpractice conference 1992 (Box 34)
  - Michigan Ensemble Theatre, Board of Friends 1982-1984 (Box 34)
  - Michigan Housing Trust Fund Board 1991-1992 (Box 34)
  - Michigan Health Care Provider Malpractice and Malpractice Insurance 1985-1992 (Box 34)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 34)
  - Moore, George July-November 1984 (Box 34)
  - Mott Foundation-American Council on Education (Box 34)
  - Moyers, William May 1987 (Box 34)
  - National Academy of Arbitrators 1992 (Box 34)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges 1987 (Box 34)
  - New York State School of Industrial and Public Relations 1982-1987 (Box 34)
  - North Carolina System Study (Box 35)
  - North Carolina University System Study Committee
    - Correspondence 1991 (Box 35)
    - Reports on Changes Adopted 1992 (Box 35)
  - Notre Dame 1983 (Box 35)
  - Nuclear Free Zone, Ann Arbor campaign 1984 (Box 35)
  - Perl, Arnold 1985-1986 (Box 35)
  - Pfister, Ed 1986 (Box 35)
  - Poland. First International Symposium on Higher Education Management: A Polish-American Dialogue 1994 (Box 35)
  - Schwarz (Sen.) John 1994 (Box 35)
    (regarding Freedom of Information and Open Meetings Act legislation)
  - Sisters of Mercy v. the City of Detroit, Dispute Settlement 1992 (Box 35)
  - Student Activism, Wingspread Conference on 1985 (Box 35)
  - "Time for Change is Now" article and related 1993 (Box 35)
  - Teachers' Guide to Television--Mock Elections 1982-1985 (Box 35)
  - United States-South Africa Leadership Exchange Program, Fleming Trip 1978 (Box 35)
  - University of Florida 1982-1985 (Box 35)
  - University of Houston System 1995-1996, 2 folders (Box 35)
  - University of Illinois 1983-1987 (Box 35)
  - University of Illinois honorary degree 2000 (Box 35)
  - University of Illinois, Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations, 50th reunion 1997 (Box 35)
  - University of the State of New York (study of graduate education) 1973-1988 (Box 35)
  - University of Wisconsin 1984-1987 (Box 35)
  - University of Wisconsin Law School 50th Reunion (Box 35)
  - University of Wisconsin Law School 50th Anniversary Fund Drive 1991-1993 (Box 35)
  - WFCR: Five College Radio, Board of Governance Review 1982, 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Wright, Robin (correspondence) (Box 35)
- Knight v. State of Alabama 1989-1994
  Knight v. State of Alabama was a federal court case that challenged numerous funding and other policies of the state's colleges and universities on the grounds that they believed were racially discriminatory. Fleming was one of five neutral expert witnesses appointed by the court to assist it in fashioning a constructive remedial decree. These experts reviewed the policies found to perpetuate segregation in Alabama's colleges and universities and recommended changes to reduce racial separation in the system. These are Fleming' files from his work on that committee.
  - Court papers, etc. re college desegregation case (Box 36)
  - Court papers, etc. re college desegregation case (Box 37)
  - Court papers, etc. re college desegregation case (Box 38)
  - Court papers, etc. re college desegregation case (Box 39)
  - Court papers, etc. re college desegregation case (Box 40)
  - Court papers, etc. re college desegregation case (Box 41)
- Publications, speeches, and reports
  Publications, Speeches, Reports includes the works of Robben Fleming up to the late 1970s. Most of the publications deal with arbitration topics. The speeches are largely concerned with educational topics. Speeches from the period when Fleming was President of the University of Michigan will be found in that series.
  - Publications: Books
    - Bernstein, Evarson, and Fleming, eds. Emergency Disputes and National Policy, 1955 (Box 42)
    - "The Significance of the Wagner Act", in Derber and Young, eds. Labor and the New Deal, 1957 (Box 42)
    - Edelman and Fleming The Politics of Wage-Price Decisions: a four-country analysis, 1965 (Box 42)
  - Publications: Books (Reviews)
    - The Politics of Wage-Price Decisions (Box 42)
    - The Labor Arbitration Process (also includes Memorandum of Agreement) (Box 42)
  - Publications: Articles
    - 1949-1962 (Box 42)
    - 1962-1974 (Box 42)
    - Later articles (Box 42)
  - Speeches
    - 1955-1966 (includes undated speech) (Box 42)
    - [1967-1979 speeches in University of Michigan President series] (Box 42)
    - 1979-1989 1993, 6 folders (Box 42)